YORDANOS **DEREJE**

Contact

Email: Jordanoswork2021@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/jordanos

Phone: 251-919803164

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/yordanos-dereje

Summary

Hi, I'm Yordanos, a full-stack developer with over five years of industry experience. Since earning my computer science degree, I've contributed to numerous software projects, leading up to my role as CTO at Qbetpro. In this position, I led the project from inception to delivery. My passion lies in creating high-quality, rigorously tested applications and systems that are optimized for lightning-fast performance on any hardware.

Education

Unity University 2017 - 2021

Bachelor of Computer Science

• **Courses:** Assembly, C++, Java, OOP, Compilers, Algorithms, Data Structures, SQL, Database design, Computer Architecture, Operating Systems, System design, Machine learning.

Recent Project

CTO and Full-stack developer Oct 2023 – present

Qbetpro - Virtual game and betting platform

• QBetPro is a global technology and software company that specializes in the development and supply of virtual games designed to **empower** both **platform owners** and **shop operators**. It offers a unique combination of **scalability, profitability, and data-driven insights**.

Key Features:

- Multi-tenant architecture: Cater to a diverse range of clients with customizable branding and game offerings.
- Shop management: Equip shop operators with the tools they need to thrive, including individual game instances and dedicated profit generation algorithms.
- Real-time analytics: Gain invaluable insights from shop and tenant performance with in-depth, real-time data at your fingertips.
- Profitable outcomes: The proprietary system generates odds and outcomes specifically designed to
 ensure shop profitability.
- **Customizations:** Customizable game rules and algorithms tailored to each shop.
- Localization: Time-zone and Currency are available for every country which will enable the system to scale globally.
- I was **involved** in designing the system architecture, managing the engineering team and building the MVP.
- · Handling more than 100k requests hourly with 0% downtime.
- **Technologies**: Python, Django, Gunicorn, Pytest, Locust, NodeJS, ReactJS, Electron, Celery, Flower, Redis, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker-compose, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana, Bash, Git, GitHub Self-hosted workflow runner and CI/CD.
- · Demo:
 - Qbetpro

Professional Experience

AWURA computing Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (Remote)

Full-stack developer (Python, ReactJS) Aug 2022 - Nov 2023

__.

OwlEvents - Event management SaaS app

• Owl Events is a platform that enables businesses to organize events, sell tickets, find vendors, rent spaces, monitor also manage attendees.

- In three months, after being launched, Owl Events has secured prominent organizers and sold over 11,000 event tickets.
- I was **involved** in leading the front-end team and designing the overall system structure.
- Our team designed and implemented the portal web app that event organizers and vendors interact with. The portal lets organizers post and manage events, manage users (Securities, Ticket sellers...), In depth real-time analytics, create email templates for advertisement and more.
- **Technologies**: ReactJS, Material UI, Web-sockets, Redux, React-testing-library, Cypress, Django, locust, Celery, Redis, RabbitMQ, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker-compose, Nginx, GitHub, Self-hosted workflow runner and CI/CD.
- Portal website: https://portal.owlevents.app
- Mobile app: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.awuraplc.owlevents&pcampaignid=web share

MuluG - Hospital management SaaS app

- MuluG is a hospital management system that let physicians track their patient health in a convenient way. In addition to the basic hospital management functionalities, MuluG introduced dynamic follow-up forms (just like google forms), assessment forms that are submitted after every patient visit, customer support availability for patients, analytics and more.
- I was **involved** in leading both the engineering team, doing code reviews, designing the system architecture and setting up CI/CD.
- **Technologies**: ReactJS, Material UI, Redux, React-testing-library, Cypress, Django, Celery, Redis, PostgreSQL, Docker, Docker-compose, Nginx, GitHub, Self-hosted workflow runner and CI/CD.
- Demo: https://drive.google.com/file/d/13wE3YEMevGAhspOSzJwMHNCna5sOITR0/view?usp=sharing

iWork Technologies Denver, Colorado (Remote)

Full-stack developer and automation engineer (Python, ReactJS) Apr 2021 – Sept 2022

Automation engineer for post-quantum cryptography system

- It is a system that proactively addresses cybersecurity concerns anticipated with the development of stable quantum computing. Utilizing a multi-tenant architecture, it caters to high-priority targets of cyberattacks, including financial institutions and government agencies, by providing robust security solutions.
- I was **involved** in building tools with the automation team.
- Our team leveraged multiple technologies and built tools that test the whole cluster periodically and generates a report. It then sends a notification containing the test report for everyone through slack and email, and also alerts everyone if anything is wrong.
- **Technologies**: Python, NodeJS, Bash scripts, WASM, Testrail, Envoy, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, Ansible, SonarQube, Aws, Gitlab, CI/CD,

Rica Technologies Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (On-site)

Full-stack developer (MERN stack) Jun 2020 – Feb 2021

Rica shopping - Ecommerce platform

- Rica Shopping offers a comprehensive e-commerce experience seamlessly blended with intuitive social features. Users can easily **discover**, **buy**, **and sell a wide range of products** directly through the platform. Additionally, Rica Shopping fosters a community atmosphere by enabling users to **share and discuss their purchases** with each other, creating a more **engaging and interactive shopping experience**.
- I was **involved** as a full-stack developer where I leveraged NodeJS and flutter to build the platform.
- Technologies: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, ReactJS, pm2, Flutter, Nginx, Aws.
- Screenshots: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1saQt89vfuXVvHCi9Sr45YbVqGFaOGkvp/view?usp=sharing

Rica ride hailing

- Rica ride is a ride hailing app where users can also collect coins on every trip they take, the more coins they collect the more prizes they are winning at the end.
- I was **involved** in implementing authentication and mass advertisement using SMS.
- Technologies: Python and NodeJS.
- Mobile app: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dispatchrica.user&pcampaignid=web_share

PrimalApps Addis Ababa, Ethiopia (Remote)

Python developer Aug 2019 - Jun 2020

__-

- **Web scrapper** Implemented a web scrapper pipeline for an e-commerce site, Realtime data was getting scrapped from a competitor website and the client got stayed up to date with new product releases.
- Telegram voice chat bot Designed, implemented and deployed a telegram voice chat bot that matches users with strangers according to their choice of discussion topic. Users can also access features such as: filtering partners with gender, after they subscribe for a small amount of fee. The bot got around 1500 users in a week
- **Telegram advertisement** Sending advertisement to targeted users with telegram API. These users are scrapped from multiple super-groups and grouped into specific pools, then advertisement will be sent to the selected pool of users based on the ads type.

Skills

- •Programming Languages: Python, JavaScript/Typescript, Go, Dart.
- •Development: Django, FastAPI, NodeJS, ReactJS, Express, Langchain, LLMs, Fiber, WebSocket, Rest/Graphql API, SQL and NoSQL databases, Redis, RabbitMQ, Celery, Nginx and more.
- •DevOps: Linux, Bash, Aws (ec2, s3, lambda), Terraform. Ansible, CI/CD, Docker, Microservices, Kubernetes, Prometheus, Grafana and more.
- •Management: Scrum methodology, Jira, Confluence and more.